Andrés Romero

PhD computer vision and parallel architectures

About

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

> **** 0178542907 **1** 0615231394

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

y andresrommmier andresromero in romeromier

Languages

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP. SIMD (SSE. AVX. Neon and Altivec)

Notions of massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

△ Interests

My research focuses on the development and acceleration of signal processing and computer vision algorithms. A key goal of my research is to develop high performance algorithms for **visual object detection**, **tracking** and texture description for real-world problems. The algorithms I have worked on require the understanding of a broad set of areas: machine learning, software engineering, computer architecture and statistics.

In total, I have more than 8 years of research experience working with signal and image processing algorithms in embedded architectures. I am familiar with ARM architectures (ARM Cortex A9 and A15) and the Texas Instruments C6000 DSP family. On those platforms I have implemented many image, voice and audio processing algorithms.

Other fields of interest to me are data science, natural language processing (NLP), data mining, information theory, complexity theory and cybernetics.

Education

2010-2013	Ph.D. in Computer Science	Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique, Université Paris Sud
-----------	----------------------------------	--

Advisors: Lionel Lacassagne and Michèle Gouiffès

Real-time multi-target tracking: A study on color-texture covariance matrices and descriptor/operator switching.

The results of this work were considered for the ITEA/Spy european project.

2006-2008 **M.Sc.** Signal Processing Instituto Politécnico Nacional (IPN)

> Advisors: Héctor Pérez Meana and Mariko Nakano Miyatake Subject: Acoustic active noise controllers in TMS320C6713DSK platforms.

2000-2005 **Telecommunications Engineering** Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)

Advisor: Bohumil Psenicka

Graduation project: Acoustic active noise cancellation.

2000 **High-school** Centro Universitario México, Mexico City

Specialization in mathematics and physics

(E) Experience

2009

2009

2013-2014	Univ	ersi	té P	Paris	s Sud,	, O r	say	Fá	acul	lty	of	Science	es		Invite	d resea	arche	r and te	acher
	_			_															

Research work: Covariance descriptor algorithm implementation on "Many-core" architectures (Xeon-Phi)

2012-2013 **ITEA/Spy European Project** R&D engineer

Tracking and pedestrian re-identification module, project in collaboration between CASSIDEAN, EOLAN, ENSTA and IEF, Université Paris Sud

R&D engineer

Visiting Student

Minalum de México S.A. de C.V.

Brush-less DC motor controller development using PIC's

Czech Technical University in Prague, Czech Republic

Hosted by Prof. Pavel Saradnik

2007-2009 **Computer security department, DGSCA, UNAM** Software engineer

Emergency response team (CERT) system development.

2006-2007 **Qualcomm, Omnitracs, Mexico City, Mexico**

Satellite and GPS surveillance system operator

2004 Electoral Institute of Oaxaca, Oaxaca, Mexico

Software engineer

Operations engineer

Pre-electoral results system for the 2004 governor and local congress elections

About

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

andresrommmier
andresromero
andresromero
andresromier

Languages

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

Teaching experience

2013-2014 **ATER (Invited researcher and teacher)**

Courses

- · SIMD instructions for image processing,
- On-line data representations (XML, DOM, XPath, XSLT),
- · Relational data bases (SQL),
- Advanced C programming,
- · Logical component and computer architecture,
- · Scilab.

2012-2013 **Laboratory teacher**

Université Paris-Sud, France

Université Paris-Sud, France

Courses: SIMD instructions for image processing.

2005-2008 **Laboratory teacher**

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Mexico

Courses:

- Digital signal processing algorithm implementations on DSP architectures,
- · Digital and analog filtering.

Publications

Articles in peer-reviewed journals

Color tracking with contextual switching: Real-time implementation on CPU

F. Laguzet, A. Romero Mier y Terán, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

Journal of Real Time Image Processing (JRTIP) Special Issue on Real-Time Color Image Processing (2013). Springer, 2013

H, Perez-Meana, A Hybrid Noise Canceling Structure with Secondary Path Estimation

A. Romero, M. Nakano-Miyatake

WSEAS Recent Advances in Systems, Communications and Computers (2008) pp. 194–199. 2008

International peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

Total Bregman Divergence for Multiple Object Tracking.

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

IEEE, International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2013

Real-time covariance tracking algorithm for embedded systems

A. Romero Mier y Terán, L. Lacassagne, A. Hassan Zahraee, M. Gouiffès

Conference on Design & Architectures for Signal & Image Processing (DASIP) proceedings. 2013

Enhanced Local Binary Covariance Matrices ELBCM for texture analysis and object tracking

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

MIRAGE 2013, Berlin, Germany. ACM International Conference Proceedings Series, 2013

Covariance Descriptor Multiple Object Tracking and Re-Identification with Colorspace Evaluation

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

ACCV 2012 Workshops, Part II, LNCS 7729 proceedings, 2012

Feature points tracking adaptive to saturation

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

Signal and Image Processing Applications (ICSIPA), 2011 IEEE International Conference on, 2011

Synthesis of the Low-pass and High-pass Wave Digital Filters

B. Psenicka, Francisco J. García-Ugalde, A. Romero Mier Terán *ICINCO-SPSMC*, 2008

Synthesis of digital structure by matrix method

B. Psenicka, F.G. Ugalde, L.E. Salguero, A. Romero

Proceedings of the 7th IASTED International Conference on Signal and Image Processing, 2005

About

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

C 0178542907 ☐ 0615231394

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

y andresrommmier

andresromero in romeromier

Languages

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

66 References

Lionel Lacassagne, Associate Professor (MCF HDR) Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique (LRI) Université Paris Sud

▼ lionel.lacassagne@lri.fr

\(+33 0169154124

.

Michèle Gouiffès, Enseignant Chercheur Laboratoire d'Informatique pour la Mécanique et les Sciences de l'Ingénieur Université Paris Sud

\(+33 0169858113

Rubén Aquino Luna,

Information Security Sub-director, DGTIC, UNAM Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

raquino@seguridad.unam.mx

**** +52 55 56223064

.

Bohumil Psenicka, Full-time definite C-level Professor Facultad de Ingeniería, UNAM, Mexico City, Mexico Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

**** +52 55 56223064